let questions = [
	{
		"numb": 1,
		"question": "Investment can be defined as",
		"answer": "B) Use of capital on assets to receive returns",
		"options": [
			"A) Person's dedication to purchasing a house or flat",
			"B) Use of capital on assets to receive returns",
			"C) Usage of money on a production process of products and services",
			"D) Net additions made to the nation's capital stocks"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 2,
		"question": "The concept of financial management is",
		"answer": "B) All features of obtaining and using financial resources for company operations",
		"options": [
			"A) Profit maximization",
			"B) All features of obtaining and using financial resources for company operations",
			"C) Organization of funds",
			"D) Effective Management of every company"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 3,
		"question": "What is the primary goal of financial management?",
		"answer": "B) To maximise the owner's wealth",
		"options": [
			"A) To minimise the risk",
			"B) To maximise the owner's wealth",
			"C) To maximise the return",
			"D) To raise profit"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 4,
		"question": "GST is a consumption of goods and service tax based on.",
		"answer": "D) Destination",
		"options": [
			"A) Development",
			"B) Dividend",
			"C) Duration",
			"D) Destination"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 5,
		"question": "The finance manager is accountable for.",
		"answer": "C) Arrangement of financial resources",
		"options": [
			"A) Earning capital assets of the company",
			"B) Effective management of a fund",
			"C) Arrangement of financial resources",
			"D) Proper utilisation of funds"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 6,
		"question": "The market value of the shares is decided by",
		"answer": "A) The investment market",
		"options": [
			"A) The investment market",
			"B) The government",
			"C) Shareholders",
			"D) The respective companies"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 7,
		"question": "The capital budget is associated with.",
		"answer": "C) Long terms assets",
		"options": [
			"A) Long terms and short terms assets",
			"B) Fixed assets",
			"C) Long terms assets",
			"D) Short term assets"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 8,
		"question": "CAPM stands for.",
		"answer": "A) Capital asset pricing model.",
		"options": [
			"A) Capital asset pricing model.",
			"B) Capital amount printing model.",
			"C) Capital amount pricing model.",
			"D) Capital asset printing model."
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 9,
		"question": "What does financial leverage measure?",
		"answer": "C) The sensibility of EPS w.r.t % change in the EBIT level",
		"options": [
			"A) No change with EBIT and EPS",
			"B) The sensibility of EBIT with % change with respect to output",
			"C) The sensibility of EPS w.r.t % change in the EBIT level",
			"D) % variation in the level of production"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 10,
		"question": "From the below-mentioned items which are financial assets?",
		"answer": "D) B and C",
		"options": [
			"A) Machines",
			"B) Bonds",
			"C) Stocks",
			"D) B and C"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 11,
		"question": "An asset that derives value from a contractual claim is called as",
		"answer": "(b) Financial asset",
		"options": [
			"(a) Fictitious asset",
			"(b) Financial asset",
			"(c) Tangible asset",
			"(d) Real asset"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 12,
		"question": "The government finance which includes the principles and practices relating to the procurement and management of funds for Central Government, and Local bodies is known as:",
		"answer": "(a) Public finance",
		"options": [
			"(a) Public finance",
			"(b) Business Finance",
			"(c) Private Finance",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 13,
		"question": "Business finance deals with which of the following?",
		"answer": "(c) Both of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Utilize funds efficiently",
			"(b) Procuring funds from different sources on fair terms",
			"(c) Both of these",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 14,
		"question": "The managerial process which is concerned with the planning and control of financial resources is called as:",
		"answer": "(b) Finance function",
		"options": [
			"(a) Control function",
			"(b) Finance function",
			"(c) Management function",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 15,
		"question": "Financial management came into existence as a separate field of study fromâ€¦?",
		"answer": "(c) 20th century",
		"options": [
			"(a) 19th century",
			"(b) 21st century",
			"(c) 20th century",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 16,
		"question": "The financial activities which are performed regularly are known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Recurring finance functions",
		"options": [
			"(a) Non-recurring finance functions",
			"(b) Both of these",
			"(c) Recurring finance functions",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 17,
		"question": "The financial activities which are performed only on special events like promotion, amalgamation and solvency crisis are called as:",
		"answer": "(a) Non-recurring finance functions",
		"options": [
			"(a) Non-recurring finance functions",
			"(b) Recurring finance functions",
			"(c) Both of these",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 18,
		"question": "The sum of short term and long term sources of finance is known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Financial structure",
		"options": [
			"(a) Capital structure",
			"(b) Both of these",
			"(c) Financial structure",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 19,
		"question": "The sources of finance from which the quantum of required funds can be raised is/are:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Share capital",
			"(b) Trade credit",
			"(c) Debt capital",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 20,
		"question": "The decisions of investing in long term or fixed assets on the basis of cost-benefit analysis or risk-return analysis are known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Capital budgeting decisions",
		"options": [
			"(a) Working capital decisions",
			"(b) Financial Decisions",
			"(c) Capital budgeting decisions",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 21,
		"question": "Short term or current assets Decisions are known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Both",
		"options": [
			"(a) Short term investment decisions",
			"(b) Working capital decisions",
			"(c) Both",
			"(d) None"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 22,
		"question": "The decisions relating to the use of profits or income of an entity or organization are known as:",
		"answer": "(b) Dividend decisions",
		"options": [
			"(a) Finance decisions",
			"(b) Dividend decisions",
			"(c) Investment Decision",
			"(d) Any of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 23,
		"question": "The financial manager selects one or more sources of finance after proper taking into consideration of:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Cost of capital",
			"(b) Control",
			"(c) Risk",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 24,
		"question": "The profit maximization objective has been criticized on the basis of:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Ignore risk factor",
			"(b) Ignore time value of money",
			"(c) Ambiguity",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 25,
		"question": "Which is the main motive is to select activities having positive impact on society in:",
		"answer": "(c) Wealth maximization objective",
		"options": [
			"(a) Profit maximization objective",
			"(b) Welfare maximization objective",
			"(c) Wealth maximization objective",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 26,
		"question": "The social cost benefits analysis is primarily used to determine the economic benefits of the activities in forms of which of the following:",
		"answer": "(c) Shadow prices",
		"options": [
			"(a) Market prices",
			"(b) Discounted prices",
			"(c) Shadow prices",
			"(d) Augmented prices"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 27,
		"question": "Treasurer performs the functions of which of the following functions:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Credit management",
			"(b) Cash management",
			"(c) Procurement of essential funds",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 28,
		"question": "Financial controller is responsible for:",
		"answer": "(d) None of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Cash management",
			"(b) Credit management",
			"(c) Securities management",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 29,
		"question": "The degree correlation between risk and return over a longer period of time is generally:",
		"answer": "(c) Highly positive",
		"options": [
			"(a) Highly negative",
			"(b) Negative",
			"(c) Highly positive",
			"(d) No correlation"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 30,
		"question": "The appreciation in the value of security or asset is called as:",
		"answer": "(c) Capital return",
		"options": [
			"(a) Current return",
			"(b) Total return",
			"(c) Capital return",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 31,
		"question": "Current return is the ratio of annual income to:",
		"answer": "(b) Beginning price of security",
		"options": [
			"(a) Ending price of security",
			"(b) Beginning price of security",
			"(c) Difference between beginning price and ending price of security",
			"(d) Total of beginning price and ending price of security"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 32,
		"question": "The application of the probability distribution is the characteristic of possible outcomes that must be:",
		"answer": "(d) None of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Mutually inclusive",
			"(b) Collective exhausting",
			"(c) Either collective exhausting or mutually inclusive",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 33,
		"question": "The minimum expected rate of return that is needed to persuade an investor to purchase the security at given risk is which of the following?",
		"answer": "(c) Required rate of return",
		"options": [
			"(a) Risk premium",
			"(b) Risk free rate of return",
			"(c) Required rate of return",
			"(d) Inflation premium"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 34,
		"question": "The risk that arises due to use of debt by the firm causing variability of return for creditors and shareholders is:",
		"answer": "(c) Financial Risk",
		"options": [
			"(a) Call Risk",
			"(b) Liquidity Risk",
			"(c) Financial Risk",
			"(d) Default Risk"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 35,
		"question": "The variability in return on security due to changes in the level of interest rate in market is called as:",
		"answer": "(b) Interest Risk",
		"options": [
			"(a) Call Risk",
			"(b) Interest Risk",
			"(c) Liquidity Risk",
			"(d) Financial Risk"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 36,
		"question": "Cumulative wealth index measures the level of wealth of investor by taking the cumulative effect of:",
		"answer": "(d) Total return",
		"options": [
			"(a) Dividend",
			"(b) Premium",
			"(c) Total risk",
			"(d) Total return"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 37,
		"question": "Purchasing power of risk hits the investor when there are chances that the:",
		"answer": "(a) Real return on a security is less than the nominal return",
		"options": [
			"(a) Real return on a security is less than the nominal return",
			"(b) Real return on a security is equal to the nominal return",
			"(c) Real return on a security is more than the nominal return",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 38,
		"question": "Risk associated with a particular firm's operating conditions is which of the following risk?",
		"answer": "(b) Business Risk",
		"options": [
			"(a) Interest Risk",
			"(b) Business Risk",
			"(c) Financial Risk",
			"(d) Liquidity Risk"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 39,
		"question": "Not measurable time is?",
		"answer": "(a) Uncertainty",
		"options": [
			"(a) Uncertainty",
			"(b) Risk",
			"(c) Certainty",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 40,
		"question": "Which of the following risk is indicated by the beta coefficient in Financial Management?",
		"answer": "(c) Non diversifiable risk",
		"options": [
			"(a) Diversifiable risk",
			"(b) Adjusted risk",
			"(c) Non diversifiable risk",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 41,
		"question": "The risk in terms of variability in securityâ€™s total return due to some exogenous factors is known as:",
		"answer": "(b) Systematic risk",
		"options": [
			"(a) Non diversifiable risk",
			"(b) Systematic risk",
			"(c) Unsystematic risk",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 42,
		"question": "The relationship of required rate of return and risk shows the linearity in the:",
		"answer": "(a) Security market line",
		"options": [
			"(a) Security market line",
			"(b) Asset market line",
			"(c) Capital market line",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 43,
		"question": "The shares of the companies having high dividend payout ratios are:",
		"answer": "(a) Income shares",
		"options": [
			"(a) Income shares",
			"(b) Cyclical shares",
			"(c) Growth shares",
			"(d) Defensive shares"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 44,
		"question": "The smallest unit of capital is known as:",
		"answer": "(b) Share",
		"options": [
			"(a) Debenture",
			"(b) Share",
			"(c) Bond",
			"(d) Deposit"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 45,
		"question": "The valuation of equity by the discounted cash flow techniques depends on:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Expected dividends",
			"(b) Cash flows",
			"(c) Earnings",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 45,
		"question": "The Market of initial public offerings where any new share is issued is known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Primary market",
		"options": [
			"(a) Secondary market",
			"(b) Money market",
			"(c) Primary market",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 46,
		"question": "The techniques used by fundamental analysts to valuate the equity shares is/are:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Asset based techniques",
			"(b) Comparable techniques",
			"(c) Present value techniques",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 47,
		"question": "The model that assumes the normal rate of growth over an indefinite time horizon is:",
		"answer": "(b) Gordon Model",
		"options": [
			"(a) H model of equity valuation",
			"(b) Gordon Model",
			"(c) Free cash flow models",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 48,
		"question": "Which models generally applied by the fundamental analysts to valuate the equity share are called to be?",
		"answer": "(c) Both of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Relative valuation models",
			"(b) Dividend valuation models",
			"(c) Both of these",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 49,
		"question": "The balance sheet valuation is a:",
		"answer": "(c) Historical approach",
		"options": [
			"(a) Nominal approach",
			"(b) Futuristic approach",
			"(c) Historical approach",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 50,
		"question": "The discounted cash flow is which of the following approach?",
		"answer": "(b) Forward approach",
		"options": [
			"(a) Backward approach",
			"(b) Forward approach",
			"(c) Earnings approach",
			"(d) Risk approach"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 51,
		"question": "The model that derives the value of stock from the pricing of comparable assets is called as:",
		"answer": "(b) Relative valuation model",
		"options": [
			"(a) Composite valuation model",
			"(b) Relative valuation model",
			"(c) Growth valuation model",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 52,
		"question": "The current dividends are assumed to be equal to future dividends in case of:",
		"answer": "(b) Perpetuity",
		"options": [
			"(a) Variable growth",
			"(b) Perpetuity",
			"(c) Constant growth",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 53,
		"question": "The comparison of various facets of the same firm over a period of time is called as:",
		"answer": "(c) Time series analysis",
		"options": [
			"(a) Cross sectional analysis",
			"(b) Technical analysis",
			"(c) Time series analysis",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 54,
		"question": "The constant divided growth model is propounded by which of the following?",
		"answer": "(a) Fama",
		"options": [
			"(a) Fama",
			"(b) William Sharpe",
			"(c) Gordon",
			"(d) Miller"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 55,
		"question": "What indicates the relationship between interest rate and reinvestment rate?",
		"answer": "(b) Positive",
		"options": [
			"(a) Zero",
			"(b) Positive",
			"(c) Negative",
			"(d) Perfectly negative"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 56,
		"question": "The investment made in fixed assets is known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Capital expenditure",
		"options": [
			"(a) Revenue expenditure",
			"(b) Rental Expenditure",
			"(c) Capital expenditure",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 57,
		"question": "The main components of capital budgeting are:",
		"answer": "(c) Capital expenditure & Budgeting",
		"options": [
			"(a) Capital expenditure",
			"(b) Budgeting",
			"(c) Capital expenditure & Budgeting",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 58,
		"question": "The investment decisions which are concerned with the allocation of funds of an entity to the long term investment proposals are known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Both of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Capital investment",
			"(b) Capital budgeting",
			"(c) Both of these",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 59,
		"question": "The decisions which are concerned with allocation of funds to the short term investment proposals are known as:",
		"answer": "(b) Working capital decisions",
		"options": [
			"(a) Capital investment",
			"(b) Working capital decisions",
			"(c) Capital budgeting",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 60,
		"question": "The art of making plans in quantitative manner to ensure profitability and growth is known as:",
		"answer": "(a) Budgeting",
		"options": [
			"(a) Budgeting",
			"(b) Discounting",
			"(c) Compounding",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 61,
		"question": "Financial managers consider capital budgeting as a very important function of finance due to:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Large Investment",
			"(b) Long term Effect on Profitability",
			"(c) Long Term Commitment of Funds",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 62,
		"question": "The capital expenditure decisions encompass the decisions relating to:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Independent investment proposals",
			"(b) Mutually exclusive investment proposals",
			"(c) Contingent investment proposals",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 63,
		"question": "The capital budgeting decision generally involves - investment of funds.",
		"answer": "(b) Huge",
		"options": [
			"(a) Meager",
			"(b) Huge",
			"(c) Small",
			"(d) No"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 64,
		"question": "The examples of capital expenditure is:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Purchase of fixed assets",
			"(b) Replacement of fixed assets",
			"(c) Alteration to the fixed assets",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 65,
		"question": "The Nature of capital expenditure decisions may be:",
		"answer": "(c) Irreversible",
		"options": [
			"(a) Reversible",
			"(b) Routine",
			"(c) Irreversible",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 66,
		"question": "The process of owning and acquiring economic resources to generate income in future is called as:",
		"answer": "(c) Investment decision",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financing decision",
			"(b) Dividend decision",
			"(c) Investment decision",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 67,
		"question": "Which of the following network techniques help in monitoring the implementation of the approved proposals?",
		"answer": "(c) Both of the above",
		"options": [
			"(a) Critical Path Method (CPM)",
			"(b) Programme Evaluation Review Technique (PERT)",
			"(c) Both of the above",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 68,
		"question": "The criteria that do not take time value of money into consideration are known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Traditional criteria",
		"options": [
			"(a) Discounted criteria",
			"(b) Either (a) or (b)",
			"(c) Traditional criteria",
			"(d) Neither (a) nor (b)"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 69,
		"question": "The final approval of investment proposals is based on:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial viability",
			"(b) Economic constituents",
			"(c) Profitability",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 70,
		"question": "The overall objective of capital budgeting is to:",
		"answer": "(a) Maximize the shareholders' wealth",
		"options": [
			"(a) Maximize the shareholders' wealth",
			"(b) Reduce costs",
			"(c) Increase revenues",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 71,
		"question": "The payback period method gives much emphasis on:",
		"answer": "(c) Liquidity",
		"options": [
			"(a) Profitability",
			"(b) Whole life earnings",
			"(c) Liquidity",
			"(d) Time factor"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 72,
		"question": "The traditional criteria encompass:",
		"answer": "(c) Both of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Accounting rate of return",
			"(b) Payback period",
			"(c) Both of these",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 73,
		"question": "The length of time needed to recover the initial cash outlay of the investment proposal is called as:",
		"answer": "(a) Payback period",
		"options": [
			"(a) Payback period",
			"(b) Return period",
			"(c) Accounting period",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 74,
		"question": "The criterion which measures the profitability in terms of relation between income and investment is known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Accounting rate of return",
		"options": [
			"(a) Payback period",
			"(b) Time value of money",
			"(c) Accounting rate of return",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 75,
		"question": "A discount rate that equates the present value of inflows to the present value of cash outflows is known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Internal rate of return",
		"options": [
			"(a) Rate of return",
			"(b) Cost of capital",
			"(c) Internal rate of return",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 76,
		"question": "The advantages of accounting rate of return criterion are:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Takes whole life earnings",
			"(b) Emphasis on profitability",
			"(c) Easy computation",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 77,
		"question": "The criterion which compares the present value of cash inflows with the present value of cash outflows is known as:",
		"answer": "(a) Present value criterion",
		"options": [
			"(a) Present value criterion",
			"(b) Accounting rate of return criterion",
			"(c) Payback period criterion",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 78,
		"question": "What is the acceptance rule of payback period?",
		"answer": "(b) Select the investment proposal with lowest payback period among all investment proposals",
		"options": [
			"(a) Select the investment proposal with highest payback period among all investment proposals",
			"(b) Select the investment proposal with lowest payback period among all investment proposals",
			"(c) Either (a) or (b)",
			"(d) Neither (a) nor (b)"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 79,
		"question": "The merit of present value method is/are:",
		"answer": "(b) Both of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) It takes time factor into consideration",
			"(b) It takes whole life earnings",
			"(c) Both of these",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 80,
		"question": "In which market the newly issued securities and shares are bought or sold during initial public offerings (IPO)?",
		"answer": "(a) Primary market",
		"options": [
			"(a) Primary market",
			"(b) Secondary market",
			"(c) Insurance markets",
			"(d) Investment Market"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 81,
		"question": "The equity shares are classified as blue chip shares, growth shares, income shares, cyclical shares, defensive shares, and speculative shares by the stock market on the basis of their:",
		"answer": "(b) Both of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Risk exposure",
			"(b) Both of these",
			"(c) Return potential",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 82,
		"question": "Which market provides instruments for managing the financial risk?",
		"answer": "(c) Derivatives market",
		"options": [
			"(a) Money market",
			"(b) Bond market",
			"(c) Derivatives market",
			"(d) Commodity market"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 83,
		"question": "Which market provides finance for long term purposes?",
		"answer": "(b) Capital market",
		"options": [
			"(a) Money market",
			"(b) Capital market",
			"(c) Both of these",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 84,
		"question": "Equity shares are known as:",
		"answer": "(b) Ownership securities",
		"options": [
			"(a) Debt securities",
			"(b) Ownership securities",
			"(c) Both",
			"(d) None of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 85,
		"question": "Which market provides finance for short term purposes?",
		"answer": "(a) Money market",
		"options": [
			"(a) Money market",
			"(b) Capital market",
			"(c) Both of these",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 86,
		"question": "In which market are existing securities bought and sold?",
		"answer": "(c) Secondary market",
		"options": [
			"(a) Donation markets",
			"(b) Primary market",
			"(c) Secondary market",
			"(d) Insurance Market"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 87,
		"question": "A lease agreement which gives only a limited right to the lessee to use the asset is called:",
		"answer": "(a) Operating lease",
		"options": [
			"(a) Operating lease",
			"(b) Financial lease",
			"(c) Leveraged leasing",
			"(d) Sale and lease back"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 88,
		"question": "Arrear Dividend is paid to the Preference share otherwise known as:",
		"answer": "(b) Cumulative preference shares",
		"options": [
			"(a) Participate Preference share",
			"(b) Cumulative preference shares",
			"(c) Noncumulative preference shares",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 89,
		"question": "The creditor ship security with specified period, fixed rate of return, low capital uncertainty with perfect income certainty is known as:",
		"answer": "(a) Debentures/Bonds",
		"options": [
			"(a) Debentures/Bonds",
			"(b) Preference shares",
			"(c) Ordinary/Equity Shares",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 90,
		"question": "Preference shares are hybrid instruments containing the features of:",
		"answer": "(b) Debentures & Equity Shares",
		"options": [
			"(a) Debentures",
			"(b) Debentures & Equity Shares",
			"(c) Equity Shares",
			"(d) None of these"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 91,
		"question": "A transaction where goods are delivered to the purchaser immediately and purchase price is to be made as installment wise.",
		"answer": "(c) Hire purchase",
		"options": [
			"(a) Leasing",
			"(b) Causing",
			"(c) Hire purchase",
			"(d) Tire Purchase"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 92,
		"question": "The responsibility of use and maintenance of the asset in operating lease lies with the:",
		"answer": "(a) Lessor",
		"options": [
			"(a) Lessor",
			"(b) Lessee",
			"(c) Messi",
			"(d) Desi"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 93,
		"question": "The long term and non-cancellable lease where the ownership may be transferred to lessee is:",
		"answer": "(d) Financial lease",
		"options": [
			"(a) Operating lease",
			"(b) Sale and lease back",
			"(c) Leveraged leasing",
			"(d) Financial lease"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 94,
		"question": "In which of the following lease agreements does the owner of an asset sell the asset to a party (the buyer), who in turn leases back the same asset to the owner in consideration of some lease rentals?",
		"answer": "(b) Sale and lease back",
		"options": [
			"(a) Insurance Lease",
			"(b) Sale and lease back",
			"(c) Operating lease",
			"(d) Financial lease"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 95,
		"question": "The smallest unit of the capital is known as:",
		"answer": "(a) Share",
		"options": [
			"(a) Share",
			"(b) Unit",
			"(c) Account",
			"(d) Bond"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 96,
		"question": "Newly issued shares are related to:",
		"answer": "(a) Primary market",
		"options": [
			"(a) Primary market",
			"(b) Secondary market",
			"(c) Daily market",
			"(d) Fish market"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 97,
		"question": "Stock market is a:",
		"answer": "(b) Capital Market",
		"options": [
			"(a) Money Market",
			"(b) Capital Market",
			"(c) Insurance Market",
			"(d) Donation Market"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 98,
		"question": "Full Form of UTI:",
		"answer": "(c) Unit Trust of India",
		"options": [
			"(a) Unique Tattoo of India",
			"(b) Unique Table in India",
			"(c) Unit Trust of India",
			"(d) Unit Technique in Insurance"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 99,
		"question": "The costs independent of production, sales or earnings are known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Fixed costs",
		"options": [
			"(a) Variable costs",
			"(b) Total costs",
			"(c) Fixed costs",
			"(d) Marginal costs"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 100,
		"question": "Through leverage analysis, the financial manager measures the relationship between:",
		"answer": "(d) Costs, sales, revenue and earning",
		"options": [
			"(a) Cost and earning",
			"(b) Sales revenue and earning",
			"(c) Costs and sales revenue",
			"(d) Costs, sales, revenue and earning"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 101,
		"question": "The relationship between the operating income and earnings per share is known as:",
		"answer": "(a) Financial leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial leverage",
			"(b) Operating leverage",
			"(c) Composite leverage",
			"(d) Working capital leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 102,
		"question": "Rent of building, salary of manager, lease payment, depreciation and property taxes are examples of:",
		"answer": "(c) Fixed operating costs",
		"options": [
			"(a) Both of the above",
			"(b) Variable operating costs",
			"(c) Fixed operating costs",
			"(d) None of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 103,
		"question": "The percentage change in the net operating income resulting from a percentage change in the sales is known as:",
		"answer": "(d) Degree of operating leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Degree of combined leverage",
			"(b) Degree of financial leverage",
			"(c) Degree of working leverage",
			"(d) Degree of operating leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 104,
		"question": "The ability of an entity to use fixed financial charges to magnify the effects of changes in operating income on the earning per share is known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Financial leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Composite leverage",
			"(b) Operating leverage",
			"(c) Financial leverage",
			"(d) Working capital leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 105,
		"question": "The percentage change in taxable profit as a result of percentage change in operating profit is known as:",
		"answer": "(a) Degree of financial leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Degree of financial leverage",
			"(b) Degree of operating leverage",
			"(c) Degree of working leverage",
			"(d) Degree of combined leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 106,
		"question": "The level of earnings before interest and taxes at which earning per share is zero is:",
		"answer": "(a) Financial break-even point",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial break-even point",
			"(b) Indifferent point",
			"(c) Both of the above",
			"(d) None of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 107,
		"question": "Which leverage measures the relationship between the sales revenue and the taxable income?",
		"answer": "(b) Composite leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial leverage",
			"(b) Composite leverage",
			"(c) Operating leverage",
			"(d) Working capital leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 108,
		"question": "Which leverage measures the sensitivity of return on investment to changes in the level of current assets?",
		"answer": "(d) Working capital leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Operating leverage",
			"(b) Composite leverage",
			"(c) Financial leverage",
			"(d) Working capital leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 109,
		"question": "The cost dependent on the level of production, sales or earnings is known as:",
		"answer": "(a) Variable costs",
		"options": [
			"(a) Variable costs",
			"(b) Total costs",
			"(c) Fixed costs",
			"(d) Marginal costs"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 110,
		"question": "The relationship between the sales revenue and operating income is known as:",
		"answer": "(d) Operating leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial leverage",
			"(b) Composite leverage",
			"(c) Working capital leverage",
			"(d) Operating leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 111,
		"question": "The study of the relation between the sales revenue and earning per share is done with the help of:",
		"answer": "(c) Composite leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial leverage",
			"(b) Working capital leverage",
			"(c) Composite leverage",
			"(d) Operating leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 112,
		"question": "Raw material costs, wages, electricity and other utilities are examples of:",
		"answer": "(a) Variable operating costs",
		"options": [
			"(a) Variable operating costs",
			"(b) Fixed costs",
			"(c) Total costs",
			"(d) Marginal costs"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 113,
		"question": "Which leverage can be determined with the help of break-even analysis?",
		"answer": "(d) Operating leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial leverage",
			"(b) Composite leverage",
			"(c) Working capital leverage",
			"(d) Operating leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 114,
		"question": "When an entity earns more on the assets purchased with the fixed cost funds than the fixed costs of their use, it is known as:",
		"answer": "(c) Both of the above",
		"options": [
			"(a) Favorable financial leverage",
			"(b) Positive financial leverage",
			"(c) Both of the above",
			"(d) None of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 115,
		"question": "Trading on equity is possible only when the entity uses:",
		"answer": "(a) Financial leverage",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial leverage",
			"(b) Composite leverage",
			"(c) Working capital leverage",
			"(d) Operating leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 116,
		"question": "The point at which different sets of debt-equity ratios give the same earning per share is known as:",
		"answer": "(b) Indifferent point",
		"options": [
			"(a) Financial breakeven point",
			"(b) Indifferent point",
			"(c) Both of the above",
			"(d) None of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 117,
		"question": "Financial decisions involve:",
		"answer": "Investment, financing and dividend decisions",
		"options": [
			"Investment, financing and dividend decisions",
			"Investment, financing and sales decisions",
			"Financing, dividend and cash decisions"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 118,
		"question": "Factoring is a method of raising:",
		"answer": "Short term finance",
		"options": [
			"Long term finance",
			"Medium term finance",
			"Short term finance"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 119,
		"question": "Financing leverage is calculated as:",
		"answer": "Earnings before interest and tax/Earnings after tax",
		"options": [
			"Contribution/Earnings before interest and tax",
			"Earnings before interest and tax/Earnings before tax",
			"Earnings before interest and tax/Earnings after tax"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 120,
		"question": "Debenture securities carry:",
		"answer": "4. Interest only",
		"options": [
			"1. Voting rights and dividend",
			"2. Interest and voting rights",
			"3. Interest and dividend",
			"4. Interest only"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 121,
		"question": "The prime objective of an enterprise is:",
		"answer": "2. Maximization of owner's equity",
		"options": [
			"1. Maximization of sales",
			"2. Maximization of owner's equity",
			"3. Maximization of profit"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 122,
		"question": "Non-members can trade in securities at stock exchanges with the help of:",
		"answer": "2. Brokers",
		"options": [
			"1. Jobbers",
			"2. Brokers",
			"3. Authorized clerk"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 123,
		"question": "Financial Leverage is intended to:",
		"answer": "4. Increase return on capital employed and net equity",
		"options": [
			"1. Increase return on capital employed",
			"2. Increase net equity return",
			"3. Decrease volatility in return",
			"4. Increase return on capital employed and net equity"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 124,
		"question": "The extent to which an organization uses fixed cost in its cost structure is called:",
		"answer": "2. Financial leverage",
		"options": [
			"1. Overall leverage",
			"2. Financial leverage",
			"3. Fixed Leverage",
			"4. Operating leverage"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 125,
		"question": "Use of fixed interest securities in the capital structure is called:",
		"answer": "2. Financial leverage",
		"options": [
			"1. Operating leverage",
			"2. Financial leverage",
			"3. Overall leverage",
			"4. None of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 126,
		"question": "What are the considerations in designing capital structure of a corporate?",
		"answer": "4. All of the above",
		"options": [
			"1. Trading on Equity",
			"2. Cost of capital",
			"3. Profitability",
			"4. All of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 127,
		"question": "Capital structure designing has nothing to do with:",
		"answer": "4. Transferability",
		"options": [
			"1. Profitability",
			"2. Solvency",
			"3. Flexibility",
			"4. Transferability"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 128,
		"question": "Capital structure represents:",
		"answer": "1. Ratio between different forms of capital",
		"options": [
			"1. Ratio between different forms of capital",
			"2. All liabilities",
			"3. All assets",
			"4. Assets and liabilities"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 129,
		"question": "Cost of capital does not mean:",
		"answer": "4. Money paid to SEBI for permission to acquire capital",
		"options": [
			"1. Cut off rate decided by management",
			"2. Rate of interest",
			"3. Expectations of investors for dividend",
			"4. Money paid to SEBI for permission to acquire capital"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 130,
		"question": "In dividend decision, which of the following is not very much relevant?",
		"answer": "1. Capital market conditions",
		"options": [
			"1. Capital market conditions",
			"2. Industry practice",
			"3. Availability of disposable profit",
			"4. Investor's expectations for dividend"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 131,
		"question": "M - M Theory in a perfect market suggests that dividend payment -",
		"answer": "2. Has no impact on the value of a firm",
		"options": [
			"1. Has a positive impact on the value of firm",
			"2. Has no impact on the value of a firm",
			"3. Has a negative impact on the value of firm",
			"4. Has negligible impact on the firm"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 132,
		"question": "The rate of discount at which NPV of a project becomes zero is also known as",
		"answer": "2. Internal Rate of Return",
		"options": [
			"1. Average Rate of Return",
			"2. Internal Rate of Return",
			"3. Alternative Rate of Return",
			"4. None of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 133,
		"question": "Who propounded the dividend irrelevance theorem to share valuation?",
		"answer": "2. Modigliani and Miller",
		"options": [
			"1. Myron Gordon",
			"2. Modigliani and Miller",
			"3. James E. Walter",
			"4. None of the above"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 134,
		"question": "Consider the following steps in the process of Capital Budgeting:\n1. Identification of investment proposals.\n2. Fixing priorities.\n3. Evaluation of various proposals.\n4. Selection and preparation of Capital Budgets.\n5. Implementation.\n6. Performance Review.\nWhich of the sequence of these steps is correct?",
		"answer": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6",
		"options": [
			"1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6",
			"2, 1, 3, 4, 5, 6",
			"1, 3, 2, 4, 5, 6",
			"1, 4, 3, 2, 5, 6"
		]
	},
	{
		"numb": 135,
		"question": "Funds are financial resources in the form of:",
		"answer": "(d) All of these",
		"options": [
			"(a) Corporate capital",
			"(b) Business funds",
			"(c) Cash Equivalents",
			"(d) All of these"
		]
	},			
]